THE INVASION
I told you, I no longer have any sulfonamide.
Just be sure to send me some.
Look, we could see hundreds of
refugees in the coming days.
So I need emergency kits, dressings, serum ...
I know the trains won't be running.
Send me a lorry, an ambulance anything.
The Germans have reached Besançon.
My God !
It's the end.
And you're still going to go
and deliver the child ?
A baby won't wait because the Germans are coming !
As soon as the line's restored
call the Besançon depot for more drugs.
And cancel all visits.
.. except those which seem vital..
What do I tell them ? The Germans are arriving ?
No, absolutely not. That will trigger a panic.
You could say that...
I'll think of something.
Papa just called, he says the Germans are in Lyon.
The Germans have been threatening for two weeks.
I can't see them coming here.
We'll have to send the boy away.
Yes, but I don't want him to go
with the school. It's not wise.
What are you talking about.
The Boches are only 100km away.
... but the army can't advance
100km in a day !
What do you know about it ?
But Maman, all my friends are going.
Are you sure it's not risky ?
A hundred kilometres  Jeannine !
Good. Since it makes you happy.
OK.
Get going. Get ready, pal.
And don't forget your gas mask. Eh ?
Madame, Madame. It's terrible, the butcher
called. The chickens are still at Lons-le-Saunier.
It's unbelievable, Sarah. Every time the same.
I can't trust you with anything !
You can use the piece of beef.
No. We're not eating beef on my birthday !
Good, get three chickens from the farm.
It won't be Bresse chicken, but ....
I'm not going 20km for three chickens !
But it's not just for three chickens,
It's for me.
OK, I'll go there before going to the sawmill.
I love you.
Me too.
Marie !
Marie ?
Yes, Monsieur Schwartz, I'm here.
I'm here.
I'm not disturbing you ?
No.
Any news of Lorrain?
Nothing since his letter of the 3rd.That means nothing.
The radio says the Post is backed up.
I need three chickens for Jeannine's birthday.
There's a problem at the butchers.
You're sure I'm not disturbing you.
No, no, I'm just trying
to move the living room chest.
It's heavy.
I'll help you, Marie.
That's good... Now you.
There.
What does it take to move this thing ?
I don't know.
While milking this morning I thought it would
be better along the wall, by the fireplace.
Marie !
Go on then, pull.
Excuse me.
Have you seen my pears ?
Yes.
When are you going to your cousin's in the Landes ?
My mother refuses, she says it's too far.
You're sure ?
At first I pretended to sulk,
but I prefer to stay here.
That way we can stay together all Summer !
Perhaps we'll see fighting.
They're giving a concert on Friday
near St Christopher's Church.
It's an organ recital, a fantasy by Couperin.
I have two tickets.
Can I help you, Louis ?
I'll be happy to accompany you.
But do you think they will still have
the concert with all the goings-on ?
Hope springs eternal.
I've been thinking about it for months.
Since we kissed at Christmas.
We kiss every Christmas.
Yes. But this time your husband wasn't there.
What are we going to do now, Monsieur Schwartz ?
We can be less formal for a start.
No. That would be too strange for me.
My God !
Monsieur Schwartz, we're crazy to do this.
No !
I've got to go.
I want us to meet again. Soon. We need to talk.
Tomorrow about 11 am, is that OK with you ?
I'll be in the fields.
And my chickens ?
You haven't given me my chickens !
Right, Because I don't have any.
I've only a few cocks and two old laying hens,
but nothing fit for a plate.
We can stop there. What do you think ? Yes ?
We can get the snacks ready
and afterwards start the picnic under the trees.
Children !
Leaders, set the table.
And you others be careful.
Put your things down carefully.
Especially the gas masks.
... and there's even alcohol in it...
I don't believe you !
Why not ?
Because I say so !
Boys, calm down.
Stop clowning around.
Look down there. There's a gun.
Boys, get away ! It's not safe.
It could explode.
Let's go ! In file.
We could go somewhere else. Right ?
Should we go farther away ?
No, we'll stay here. It may be a booby-trap.
Our people have abandoned this stuff.
The Master says the Army left it.
What's a booby-trap ?
A booby-trap ! That would be a dirty trick.
... help your friends.....you, serve the croissants ?
There's no risk.
Children... !  Children !
Stop now. Stop. War isn't a game, come and eat.
Listen !
Look, an aircraft !
Boys. Stop. It's one of ours.
He won't see much of us.
Hello Michel.
Hello Inès.
Hello Monsieur Schwartz.
Here, I've something for you.
Good news ?
Hello Marcel.
Hello, Monsieur Schwartz.
So we're not going in July.
Even counting the Swiss traffic
I'm short at least 12 thousand.
We'll have to close for at least a month or two.
What if we carried the loads ourselves ?
By-passing Chovot transport.
No. What we save on commissions, we'd lose on petrol.
No. It's screwed. Unless your Spaniards
accept a longer day's work without increase in pay.
Listen. They're not slaves.
You think I find it funny ?
There's bound to be another solution
without turning the screws on them.
Well, I don't see a solution.
I've turned it all over three days and I don't see one.
Hey. You don't know where I can find three chickens ?
At the butchers !
Obviously.
Monsieur Schwartz it's the Police !
Monsieur Schwartz !
Monsieur le Commissaire ?
I wasn't expecting a visit from you.
Sorry to disturb you. Here's my colleague
Jean Marchetti, of the Dijon Bureau.
Marcel Larcher, my foreman. What can we do for you ?
We're investigating a Communist cell
which has formed in this area.
You've nothing better to do right now ?
Who knows ?
Sure I don't...perhaps hunt Boches rather than Frenchmen.
We simply want to find the guys
who distribute this stuff.
Communists.
You know they screwed me back in 1936...
I can assure you they're no longer in the company.
Here is one of your price lists.
You print them here I suppose.
And if you compare it with this leaflet you'll
see they were printed on the same machine.
With ink missing, there.....and there.
So you've a cell here,
printing and distributing leaflets.
This is serious.
It's impossible. I know my boys.
I've spoken to the Inspecteur about your Spaniards.
Them ! Indeed, I know them less well.
Yes. They're Republican refugees I suppose ?
Docteur Larcher ?
Why did you come ?
You didn't know one of your
workers is giving birth ?
Yes, Of course.
So. Is it going well ?
It would go well if she started to push.
The Police. They want to close the barracks.
Go on. Don't worry. It won't take long.
Translate please.
My friends.
Push.
Good day Docteur.
Push. It's going well.
It could go better.
Stand up please.
You know the Germans reached Besançon ?
The Sous-Préfet told me we're
preparing a massive counter attack.
Let's go Madame. We need to get the baby out.
Where's the interpreter, Ignacio ?
That's not a flag, is it ?
They're Communists.
It's in Spanish.
These are old things, January 39, March 39...
The printing machine !
Where's the stuff ?
The cops are here and know that we print it here.
Shit !
Pass me the stencils.
They won't take long to tumble to it.
What else is there ?
There's the Bolshevism books.
The Politburo pamphlets too.
What do we do ? Do we pack the trunk ?
With the Teutons around, I don't see where I'll go.
Hurry up....go quietly.
Him again.
Hey, don't you want us
to go with the others?
If we get demerit points for start
of school, my mother will kill me.
Don't do it. The Master's very busy already.
What's he looking for ?
Shit.
It's a Boche ! They're going to shoot us !
Are you OK, children ?
Don't move.
Bruno ?
Don't move, children.
Bruno !
Yes ?
Marceau, You're bleeding darling.
I'm hurt !
Don't worry, I'll take care of you.
Is he dead ?
Bruno .... Bruno.... Bruno. ?
What happened ?
Michaël.
What shall we do Mistress ?
Don't move.
It's OK children. Don't move.
Get back.
They'll come and get us.
I'm sure Marcel has an explanation.
Apart from him, who has access to this machine ?
I don't know, Inès, my secretary, just about everyone.
What was that ?
I don't know. It felt like an explosion !
What was it ?
They said an explosion up on the hill.
The Germans !
I think I saw tanks.
My God ! Quick, quick.
You must go home, and then leave Villeneuve.
I can't. There's the woman with the baby.
Marcel, would you oblige. Go to my house.
Tell Hortense to close the shutters and wait for me.
I'm not at your disposal !
Stop that, damnit. Your brother is stuck here.
You and your dramas.
I've got a wife too... and she's sick.
And I've to go find my kid at the school.
Good. Don't worry yourself. I'll go.
Can you take me ?
Who cares about the Communists now, OK ?
The tanks are going towards Villeneuve.
There'll be panic there.
We need to go, quick.
Help me ! Help me !
What are you doing Madame ? Lie down.
You can't get up.
Lie down, Madame.
Push here. Hard. Hard !
Come on, Madame.
Push. Come on.
It's good. I see it. I can see it's head.
Go on, push. It's coming. One more effort.
Ah, there it is.
It's a boy, Madame.
A beautiful boy.
He's beautiful. What are you going to call him ?
"Te Quiero"  (I love you)
"Te Quiero" ? Right, "Te Quiero".
He's beautiful is "Te Quiero".
Bravo, Madame.
Shit ! She's going.
She's having an haemorrhage. Quick.
Help me. In my kit there.
In the pocket on the left there's a syringe.
Get it out.
Take the needle.
There's a little bottle at the bottom.
Disinfect it with alcohol.
Go on. Pull the syringe. Suck up all the liquid.
Madame, Madame !
She's having a cardiac failure.
We need to get her to hospital.
Can you look after the baby ?
No, I don't know how. It's....
My God, I need help.
She's a Comrade who landed on our doorstep.
Now a baby. No !
Come close to me children.
Come close to me.
It's OK, Marceau, come close to me.
I want to go home.
It's only a scratch. Come on.
Your parents are going to come and look for us.
Don't worry.
They're going to come and look for us.
How many boys were there this morning ?
I don't know Mistress.
I know. There were 11, Mistress. Marinette said
there were 8 of us and 11 of them, and that..
there were 3 boys
who were going to get bored.
Yes, OK.
Get up. Stand in row. In line.
Boys on one side there, girls on the other.
Marceau, you stay with me.
Come on
Come forward.
We're missing one !
Gustave is missing.
Gustave. Gustave !
Come on, Marceau.
How can we go without Gustave ?
I don't know.
Where's Gustave.
Gustave. Gustave. Gustave. ...
Hey. Where did you come from ?
Are you frightened ? What's happened ?
I was lost.
You were lost where ?
I was with the class...
... then I ran away and I was lost.
Me too....I've been lost for a long time.
What's your name ?
Gustave.
Mine's Jacques.
You're not lost now. I've found you.
What's your spike called ?
My what ?
The town where your school is.
Villeneuve.
And where is Villeneuve ?
I don't know....over there.
Let's go, come on.
Didn't they teach you at school to listen to adults.
Eh ?   Let's go.
How could you do this to me with the leaflets ?
What leaflets ?
Listen. There's only you and Madame Inès who
know how to use the spirit printing machine.
And I don't see Madame Inès as a Bolshevik.
I don't give a damn about your political opinions.
... as long as they don't spill over into work.
But to spread propaganda at
the sawmill, right now, frankly...
I'm not a Communist.
But if my brother asks me to go and warn his wife...
Monsieur Schwartz you can't compare
family with politics.
Shit. Refugees !
No, it's Gustave's class.
Papa !
Marceau !
What happened ?
There was a plane. It fired on us Papa.
Some of the kids died.
You're bleeding ?
It's nothing.
Michaël is dead.
Gustave.
It's not him. It's not Gustave.
It's not him. He was frightened.
He had to run. We looked for him everywhere.
He's not injured. If so, we'd have seen him.
Where is he then ?
Where is he ?
He ran away.
Don't worry darling. They're going to find him
and take care of him.
Give me as many children as possible.
Good. Who's going with Monsieur Schwartz ?
You, you... you...
He has to have gone home.
It's not far.
Go on. Go on
The rest of you, stay close to me.
Don't worry, they're going to come back with help. OK
Come on.
Madame ! Open your eyes, Madame.
Stay awake, Madame.
You mustn't sleep.
I'm a doctor.     I'm a doctor.
Sergeant !
I've a patient who's haemorrhaged during labour.
She needs to be taken urgently to St Vincent Hospital.
There no longer is a hospital !
It was evacuated this morning.
But in the name of God why ?
Be calm, Monsieur.
Where's the medical station
of the 56th Infantry Division.
They don't use that for civilians' needs.
If this woman doesn't get a transfusion
in the next hour she'll die.
The 56th Division left yesterday.
Except a few regiments which went into Switzerland.
Since the Germans reached Besançon it's been panic.
Moreover they're in Villeneuve now.
You're sure ?
You haven't heard ? I think they
got as far as the railway yards.
There must be a military hospital not far away ?
There's the Army Corps at Sayolle,
20km away. But I don't know if they have blood.
2,000 francs for you if you take her to Sayolle. Now.
And our checkpoint ? We have our orders !
What is there to check ? The Germans are already here !
3,000 francs !
OK ....I don't promise they have blood.
Pierre, Jacques.
Come on, Madame. Come on.
Lean on us.
What do you want us to do ?
Especially if she stays there.
It will be safer with you.
You promise to take her to Sayolle ?
Don't worry.
Monsieur, I don't see the house.
Don't worry my dear, we're getting there.
We're getting there.
We'll all get home.
What's going on here now ?
You can't go further. There's firing everywhere.
Wait, I have to take these children to the school.
The parents will be waiting for them there.
The best is to go there on foot
via all the back lanes.
On foot ! What am I going to do with my car ?
Isn't there a way of contacting the fire brigade,
or the town hall.
Sir, there's no longer a fire brigade or town hall.
You have to sort it out yourself. Understand ?
Park there. Crouch down when you leave.
Crouch down.....get out quickly.
Marceau !      Stay together.
Look out !
Stay be hind the car.
Hide !
Watch out, watch out. Hide !
Come on. Marceau I know you're in pain, Huh ?
Watch out !
But you've to show an example. OK ?
I'm frightened Papa.
It's normal that you're frightened.
In your place I'd be frightened too.
But if you don't go, neither will your friends.
OK ? It's not complicated.
You scoot. You run across while the guys stay here.
But this morning you said it wasn't dangerous !
I'm not going to make a fool of myself
twice in the same day, eh ?
When I say "ready"....then go. OK ?
Ready ? Go. Run !
Run Marceau, run.
Run ! Go ! Run !
Go !
Where's Maman ?
She's at home darling.
You need to leave, Monsieur Schwartz.
You really need to leave !
Jeannine !
I'm going to leave you there pal. Wait for me.
Papa will come back soon.
Jeannine !
Raymond ?
Oh, you're back. How glad I am.
Maman.
My little boy !
What happened to you my love ?
We were with the teacher, and he's dead.
I told you it was dangerous.
I told you.
Yes I know. But stop it, he's not badly hurt.
I tried to phone you at the sawmill
this morning but you didn't reply.
No, I was... Sarah, what's happened ?
The soldiers, Sir.
Really ?
French...They'd been drinking.
It was horrible. What can we do ?
We must leave.
Let's pack necessities, quickly.
A child's been killed.
There's complete panic. Refugees are arriving
from everywhere. The inhabitants are leaving.
Thieves are looting.
What can we do ?
Nothing.
Wait to see what happens.
... and drink a glass or two.
I just saw a father knock down
an old man for a bottle of water.
Human nature is terrible !
It's not human nature we're
seeing in this case my boy.
... it's everything else.
Thanks.
It's funny that we meet again
under these circumstances, eh ?
You really are in Intelligence.
Yes, that's it.
We're leaving.
You want to go back to Dijon ?
I don't know. Perhaps I'd be more useful here ?
Things are getting rough.
Yes !
I only hope the Boches let us restore order.
Marcel ?
The little guy isn't here ?
No. You have to go get him at the school.
What were all those explosions ?
The Germans are there. I saw tanks.
That was the cause of the explosions.
So, it's over ?
It's an Imperialist war in our homes.
The London bankers versus the Berlin bankers.
Who cares who wins or loses.
Anyway !
The Nazis here...!
You haven't taken your asthma medicine ?
Yes.
...but with the heat and humidity...
You should go to the school, you know.
Marcel, what's happened ?
The little one...
.. it's not serious.
But during the walk to the picnic...
I'm telling you, it's not serious.
There was a problem,
For now we don't know where he is.
He wasn't injured, or he would have been found.
He must be afraid of the noise of the fighting.
He has to have hidden.
We'll find him.
My little boy.
He's smart. He's going to get out of it.
It's OK. You can come.
Come on. Come on.
Do we have to go far ?
I don't know where we're going.
What does your father do ?
He works with wood, making boards.
Boards are good. With boards you can make a coffin.
You know that. Huh ?
And you, what do you do ?
Stay there.
Don't move !
Hey !
Little one !
Come back !
Put the body in the refectory.
How is she ?
She's doing OK.
We've informed Monsieur le Curé.
Yes, yes, very good.
Poor little one.
I could do nothing. Serge, Michaël and Bruno
are dead. And I don't know where Gustave is.
Why did you go on this outing without talking to me ?
Monsieur Fournier didn't tell you ?
I never authorised it at such a time.
I'm only away for one day and...
Oh ! What are we going to tell
the parents of little Larcher ?
Monsieur Fournier didn't have the right
to decide on an outing. He knew that very well.
In addition, you're going to be
on your own in accounting for it.
My boy ? Where's my boy ?
Michaël. Michaël ? Where's Michaël ?
Where's Michaël ?
Poor little one. Lucienne. How are you doing ?
No. Leave me, No. leave me !
Geneviève, be dignified !
Get up my child.
Get up.
This horrible tragedy is a test God sends us.
My children, kneel.
...and praise the Lord.
Kneel please.
Our Father who art in heaven...
Hallowed be thy name...
Thy kingdom come...
Thy will be done...
Thy will be done....
On Earth as it is in Heaven...
Give us this day...Our daily bread...
Forgive us our trespasses...
As we forgive them...that trespass against us...
Darling, I was so scared.
Is that the baby ? Your patient this morning ?
Yes. I'll explain. Schwartz warned you ?
He told me he would.
Yes. He came with injured children.
I was busy with them.
The school class was machine-gunned by an aircraft.
There were three dead.
Good God. Whatever were they doing on the roads ?
I don't know !
His mother haemorrhaged during the delivery.
I put her in the hands of the soldiers.
We need to leave as fast as possible.
Just take absolute essentials.
My God, how small he is !
The Germans will blow up the railway yards.
They say we could stay several days in Geneva.
Time to see what happens.
But, him... ?
We'll see. I hope his mother
comes out of it alright.
Shit ! I didn't give my details
and whereabouts to the Sergeant.
What's he called ?
His mother is Spanish. She called him "Te Quiero".
Te Quiero, that's lovely.
You're sure it's wise to leave ?
Obviously we have to leave.
But this morning you said it was OK
for him to go out, and ...
Don't mix everything up please.
Now the Germans are here. Obviously we have to leave.
But to go where ?
We could go to Georges', I have the keys.
What more will we have at Charbonnières than here ?
At least it's on the other side of the river.
We'll be sheltered.
If the Germans had any difficulty
crossing rivers, they wouldn't be here.
Maman ?
I'm hungry.
That's a good sign.
Did you bring the chickens ?
Perhaps we'll have time to cook one or two en-route.
No. They didn't have any at the farm.
This residence is requisitioned for military operations.
Kindly tell me where the telephone is.
The telephone please !
It's here Monsieur.
Subtitles by R Clarke.
Whitby, Ont. Jan 2014