ON EARTH AS IT IS IN HEAVEN
The money !
They said 1,200 !
I only have that. I was wrong just now.
That's already a lot of money.
Here. Good luck.
Monsieur, we need to save some money
for the train to Marseille.
Just leave me enough for tickets.
Little details like that don't
interest me. A deal is a deal ...
... 1200 right now, or I'm off.
There .... 1200.
Too late! Sort it out yourselves .
But Monsieur, we can't cross without you.
Come back, Monsieur. Monsieur!
Monsieur
One for the Boches!
One for Pétain, or not ?
No. not Pétain.
It's for me. It's all for me.
Stop it! I have to go.
What time is your appointment?
Eight o'clock at the Kommandantur.
Ah good. I have to get over to Moutiers.
What are you going to do in Moutiers?
Mend fences with Lorrain's cousins.
And I'm changing suppliers.
You realize.                        If there hadn't been a war ...
I would have preferred that there was no war,
and we were together.
Yes. But life's never like that.
We can't keep meeting secretly like thieves!
You have Jeannine and Marceau .
If Lorrain wasn't dead,
I couldn't have continued.
In any case, I'd have stopped if he returned.
I know.
They're everywhere today.
Stop !
The idiot ! No, wait. Are you crazy, or what?
Get out! You too.
Hurry up.
Do what he says.
Do you want money ?
Shut up. And keep over to the right. Go on!
Hurry up.
Bring him to the car.
Excuse me. What are you planning to do?
The Germans are looking for him everywhere.
We need to take him in the car, immediately.
He looks badly hurt. He should see a doctor.
So that he can hand him to the Fritz's?
That.... that might be best for him.
Can't you drop that?
You can see we're not against you.
I can't go to see a doctor.
I could.
Let me see.
Marie.
I can't be late for my appointment, not today.
We can't leave him like that!
For a start we must get him out of
sight of the road. And immediately.
I know a cabin nearby.
Watch out.
Wait, it's a table.
How were you going to carry him on your own ?
Good. We'll go.
We'll go and inform a doctor.
No!
She stays here.
Well, I need to clean the wound anyway.
Otherwise it'll get infected
and then he'll be done for.
Is your meeting far?
No, two or three papers to sign. Just 5 minutes
Maybe you could go to Docteur Larcher ?
He's the Mayor, Marie.
He won't treat a pilot.
The Mayor is not to come here. OK.
He's not to come here.
Well, if you went to see Docteur Morelle, he'd come.
Good. I'll fix it.
You're OK ?
Yes.
Against the London and Vichy profiteers.
Against abusive requisitions.
Join the COMMUNISTS
Gustave, you're done ?
Then hurry up. Get rid of it.
What are all these letters?
Nothing.
Come on !
We're already late.
Are we going ?
Why did you tell me these letters were nothing ?
It doesn't concern you Gustave.
Why ?
Papa ! What?
I forgot my copybook.
It can't be true, Gustave !
Yesterday it was your pencil case, today your notebook.
I don't have time to go back home.
I'm already late.
But I'm going to be in trouble with the Mistress.
I'm going to make bad dots or lines.
I don't have time to go home, Gustave.
Maman's gone. You have to take care of your own things.
Come here.
Come here !
OK to get going ?
The German Kommandant emphasises that any aid
given to a foreign airman will be severely punished.
Do you really think there's a pilot
wandering about the area?
If the Fritz put that in the press, it's...
Are you going to sign your name ?
It's signed von Ritter, but from the mayor.
Leave it. Maria is off shopping.
Yes ?
You are Docteur Larcher ?
If this is for a consultation, I don't take
them in the morning. I'll be making my home
visits. Come back this afternoon.
No, it's not for an appointment.
Can I come in for two minutes ?
I've got people sleeping in the house.
What can I do for you ?
I'll show you.
This is my wife, Carlotta.
She gave birth in mid June in your town.
So ?
She died shortly afterwards.
Her grave is behind the church.
... with many others.
My condolences.
Thank you. Now it's my baby I'm looking for.
I found a soldier who recognized Carlotta's
photo. He told me that a Villeneuve doctor
had delivered her, and kept the baby.
And you thought it was me.
No. But as you are the Mayor I thought
you would know all the town's doctors.
Yes. Of course.
Do you have the time and place of the birth ?
The soldier told me that it was the
12th of June. I don't know the place.
And the soldier ?
He went to Switzerland.
He gave me a statement.
What is curious is that on June 12th,
there was no midwife in Villeneuve.
You were not there?
No, I was in Besançon.
It must have been a passing doctor,
during the refugee exodus.
I hadn't thought of that.
In that case, it will be hard to find him.
Sorry, I can't do anything for you.
Excuse me, but I have my visits to prepare.
Good luck.
Look at that. He's already finished everything.
That's good.
What was that?
Oh nothing.
An enquirer.
This is Herr Kruger ......
Of our Security Service.
Good day.
We're going to go over your works.
Herr Kruger wants to visit the site.
I thought it was just to sign documents.
With an appointment this morning, it's not helpful.
Unfortunately, I'm only in Villeneuve this morning.
We'll sign the papers en route.
It's a clean wound. Have you any clean cloths ?
What did he say?
The Demarcation Line. The Germans.
Here.
The Occupied Zone. Nazis. Ah, ah, ah.
Hold it.
When the doctor's treated you,
I'll get you across the line.
What are you smuggling in there?
I was speaking to you !
Mistress ?
Yes, Gustave.
Can I can go and play with my friends ?
Well, no. You're being punished.
I know, but, all the same, it's not my fault ...
Whose fault is it then?
I realized that I'd forgotten
my notebook, on my bike, on the way ...
... but Papa didn't want to go back home.
It's your father's fault then?
It due to bad luck.
When we make a mistake, Gustave,
it's very important to admit it.
Very important.
However it's you who forgot your notebook
not your Papa.
I know, but it was my Maman who
thought of everything in the morning.
I'm telling you this for your own good, Gustave.
If you forget things, you can't do well in school.
What is it, Miss ?
You can go and play Gustave.
You've been punished enough.
Thank you.
You know that I myself have a small company in Germany.
What are you in ?
Textiles. I have a works in the Ruhr.
Actually the works belongs to my wife's family.
We are going to make a detour, Monsieur Schwartz. My
men are looking for a shot-down English pilot.
It doesn't bother you ?
Not at all. You know where I stand.
Do you know the place called Les Terriers
near the river?
Yes, yes.
It's in the vicinity. You get there by Route D61.
Ah, yes. Yes, ... but ....
I know a much quicker way, a small country road.
It's not very far from here. I'll show you.
Perfect.
I'd like to see the Commissaire please.
If he's busy, it's not a big deal. I can wait.
But it's imperative that I see him.
There's an all-points search notice from Dijon.
A guy who escaped from a police van.
... more than a month ago.
.....very near here.
If he'd stayed in the vicinity
we'd have seen him.
Not if he knows how to hide .
1.70 m tall, short hair ...
Commissaire? Yes.
Go ahead. Enter .
Monsieur?
I'd like ...
... my child has disappeared.
We don't deal with missing persons here.
You should go to Long le Saunier.
Yes, I know. But he was born in Villeneuve.
I have proof that my wife had a baby
in Villeneuve on June 12th.
She didn't survive.
You have identity papers, Monsieur?
No.
I had a Pass from the Préfet of Pyrénées Orientales,
but I lost it .
How did you cross the Demarcation Line ?
Wait. His wife's dead, his kid's disappeared.
You don't need to push him !
You should go see Docteur Larcher. He's the best
midwife in the town. Everyone knows him.
Yes, I know. I just went to see him.
What did he tell you ?
He lied to me.
That's why I'm here.
What's your husband doing?
He's not my husband.
I don't give a fuck. What's he doing ?
He had a business appointment.
It wasn't supposed to take long,
but apparently it did.
He'll give us up to the Boches.
No. That's not possible.
I should go for a doctor myself.
Don't you move. Stay there.
I'm sorry.
Do you think it's my fault.
It was me who told you to go this way.
I never imagined there would be so much mud.
However, you must know the area well !
According to your Napoleon, mud
is what wins or loses battles...
... or according to Clausewitz .
I believe we need to push, Monsieur Schwartz.
Listen. In time of war we have to make do.
Here we go. If it was only the war !
I don't know what the Germans are up to today.
There are checkpoints everywhere!
What's more I queued for nothing.
Because they want us to come back another day.
Things not going well ?
There's a letter from the Academy.
Oh, but perhaps it doesn't relate to you.
If you're as worried as that,
you've only to open it.
It was addressed to you. It was poorly sealed
so I saw inside. It revokes my licence.
Revocation by letter is impossible, Lucienne .
It's a mistake, you've misread it.
Don't worry.
You're not revoked.
Not revoked ?
No.
I am.
Because of me ?
Oh no!
Because I'm Jewish.
A law was passed at the start of the month.
All Jewish officials .. But ... I ...
I didn't think that...
I didn't think...
There's surely a means of protest.
We'll write to Maréchal Pétain.
It's the Maréchal who signed
the law in question, Lucienne.
I'm sorry.
They've given me two months to leave.
... but that, I'm not sure ...
I'll see ...
I'll see .
I ... I'm really sorry.
Yes. But you've already said that.
Excuse me.
Our Father who art in heaven...
...hallowed be thy name ...
He mustn't fall asleep !
Give me some alcohol.
Help me. Make him drink.
He's dying !
If you want us to save him, you must let me go.
I don't care what you've done. It doesn't concern me.
And I want to save him as much as you do.
So now, either we let the Germans know,
or you let me get a doctor.
Monsieur Schwartz, I will let you go.
We'll visit your factory another time.
Look!
Oh, you scared me !
It's early. What are you doing here ?
Your husband is here ?
Ah, he's in consultation.
Would it bother you to fetch him ?
He doesn't like me to disturb him. So I never do .
It's pretty serious.
Don't worry, I'll keep an eye on him.
Can I get you a coffee ?
Yes, please.
Maria, can you get us three coffees?
Is there news of the pilot ?
No.
A guy came to the Commissariat this morning.
He says his wife gave birth
in Villeneuve, in June.
He's looking for the baby.
Yes. He came to see me this morning.
And ?
I couldn't do much to help him.
Leave it Maria, I will serve.
Apparently, you told him that
you weren't here on June 12th.
So I absolutely understand.
With all these upsets. Dates, all that ...
But he says he's found a witness
of a marriage that you celebrated that day.
Good. I must have been mistaken .
For sure.
Wasn't it the 13th of June that we left ?
I no longer remember.
Thank you, darling.
It's very good.
Maria found the recipe in a copy of
'Modes et Travaux'. It's based on roasted barley.
Based on barley ?
It seems that everything is
in the method of infusing it.
Listen. This man is a foreigner.
He has no papers...
...and personally, I would have discounted ...
... but Commissaire de Kervern, you know ...
Well, anyway. Check your records.
If you didn't do a delivery on June 12th, well ...
...then you didn't do a delivery on June 12th.
And if it's your word against his ...
Anyway, you know ...
I'll look.
Very good.
Ah, well, I'm sorry to have
bothered you with all this.
See you tonight.
We have no choice, Hortense.
But as he said it was your word against this man's.
But that's not the problem.
What is the problem ?
This man really is his father,
and we can't forget that.
Daniel, for me, you are his father.
You delivered him, you saved him,
you brought him to me.
I can't Daniel.
I can't !
Listen, I know how this child makes you happy ...
Not you ?
He doesn't make you happy ?
In eight years of marriage
I've never seen you so happy.
That's not the problem.
It's never the problem with you !
We must find another solution Daniel.
There is no other solution.
From the moment that man
comes to reclaim his son ...
There were refugees there during the birth.
Soldiers to whom I entrusted the mother ...
They saw me ...
De Kervern, Schwartz, even Jean
were there during the birth !
Jean will say nothing.
Hortense. I'm the mayor of Villeneuve.
Can you imagine the furore ?
The Mayor stealing a child.
You didn't steal him!
Darling.
Oh. It's all my fault. I shouldn't have ...
I shouldn't have... I didn't know at that point ...
That I couldn't live without children ?
A woman asks to see you Doctor.
She says it's urgent.
Who is it ?
A certain Marie Germain.
She speaks of a serious injury in the swamp.
She's Schwartz's tenant farmer.
You know, the woman who helped me at the church.
I haven't seen her for a long time.
Hello Docteur.
I haven't had time to offer you my condolences.
Thank you. It's the war.
There's no time for that now.
I'm sorry to bother you, but a farmhand
fell from a ladder in a hut near Les Terriers.
We think he has a spinal fracture.
Can he move his legs ?
No.  And he's cold.
We could have taken him to Dole, but if it's
his spine I believe we shouldn't move him.
It won't take you much time, just to say what it is.
A beautiful family, Peter.
It's great.
I had a wife too, a long time ago.
In Tonkin.
A cousin, a distant cousin, on my mother's side.
Her name was Genevieve.
She got under my skin.
I'm not a believer, but it
gave meaning to my life.
I worked all the time to make
deliveries. I was never there.
I came home on Sundays,
and then I was off again.
One Tuesday I returned home unexpectedly.
I'd never been back before on a Tuesday.
I broke his neck like an animal,
I still remember the sound...
...and she cried, she screamed.
A mad moment, I'd had enough.
Merde !
Deutsche...     Boches...      Deutsch...
Let's go !
Good, don't hesitate with the pricker.
OK.
Put it in  OK.
I want it just so, It's got to pierce. Good
In a couple of days it will be back to normal.
Good day, Monsieur Schwartz.
I thought you were ....
I traded my papers for those of a corpse.
In order to escape.
There was no other way.
How's Marie?
Well. Well. It will give her a shock.
What a nice surprise.
And the children?
They're with your mother-in-law.
It will give them a shock !
Ah, they'll be happy.
It's a great surprise.
I haven't had much time to think, you know.
We walked. We stumbled on dead bodies.
They still had their papers.
We took the jackets, exchanged
papers and then left.
You're wanted?
Wanted ? No but if I run into
a Boche checkpoint, I'm done for !
But with the French, it's OK.
The problem now, is...
... I don't know how I can cross the Line.
Right then, where's your injured man ?
I don't know. I don't understand.
You're completely crazy.
Do you realize the risk you've taken,
and made me take ?
I'm sorry to have lied to you,
but you wouldn't have come.
Well, of course I wouldn't have come !
This is pure thoughtlessness.
The war is over, Marie.
Excuse me. But if the war was over Docteur,
this man wouldn't be here.
He's very badly injured in fact. Is that right ?
Yes.
We need to take him to the Germans.
He has a better chance to get well.
And whose is this cabin, huh?
I have no idea, a guy that I don't know.
We'll go via the Sentier des Amourelles.
It's longer but safer.
Promise me to never do such a stupid thing again.
Thank you, Doctor.
I don't understand why you take
such risks for a tenant farmer !
Speak lower, Sarah can hear us.
Yes, well, I didn't say anything wrong.
He came to find me. What else did you want me to do ?
Give him up to the Germans ?
Between handing him to the Germans, and crossing
the line with him, there's no middle way.
The Company can pass without a problem.
It's Muller on guard. He likes me.
In addition he goes on leave tonight.
He won't ask any questions.
And if it's not him ?
You say they sometimes change at the last moment.
Stop it, do you think I like to do this ?
No.
I just don't understand why you are doing it.
Because in life, when we make commitments,
we have to fulfill them.
We need to cross. The Boches are there.
I'll carry you.
Excuse me. I'm sorry.
Your wife?  Peter ! I don't understand Peter.
Above all don't speak. Just look at me, and smile.
That's good. You can pass. Good day.
You've had a good day Monsieur Schwartz ?
Very good. Thank you.
He has no Ausweis. He's a technician
that I'm taking over to a subcontractor.
Ah no, not today. No Ausweis, no passage!
Oh, That's too bad. I really need Monsieur Germain.
It's due to a request from Kommandant von Ritter.
I'm warning you. The Kommandant will not
be happy if you don't let him go.
Good.  Wait.
Not possible. You must have an Ausweis
signed by the Kreiskommandant. Sorry.
Well, call the Kreiskommandant. You'll see.
Not today.
I'm sorry, but we can't get across.
It's probably due to this British pilot affair.
Now what?
We make a U-turn.
Except that the Gendarme will get excited.
He'll ask for your papers, or worse.
The problem is that with the excuse I gave,
we can't try and cross again for some time.
We'll have to wait a few days...
...or even weeks.
You can go across. I gave them big story that worked.
It a present Monsieur Schwartz.
Present to celebrate my Leave.
Ah. that's very nice, I owe you one.
Thank you, Monsieur Schwartz.
I'll never forget what you've done.
Say... no offence ... you work for the Germans ...
It's thanks to that, that we got across. OK ?
An escaped French soldier !
Welcome to France Messieurs, and bravo !
I'll call you when the bath
is ready, Madame.
Good evening Monsieur.
Yes, my baby. It's Maria
taking care of you tonight.
Huh ! Are you happy ?
I'm really sorry to have questioned you just now.
You can't do otherwise. You're doing your job .
Yes. However, it's still a funny way
to thank you for your hospitality and kindness.
That man, how is he?
I didn't see him for very long you know.
Do you think he would make
a good father for Te Quiero ?
In any case, what I know is that
you're a good mother for him.
Don't twist the knife in the wound.
I dread the idea of him not being here.
You'd be ready to go to any lengths to keep him?
I don't know.
Anyway, Daniel ...
No. There is nothing to be done.
We received a wanted notice today ...
An escaped prisoner.
So he isn't your guy of course, but ...
the description matches quite well ....
... same size, same hair color ...
It only takes a call to the Sûreté at Besançon.
I know them well.
And if I present it the right way, well ...
... he'll go to 'devil knows where'.
For at least, I don't know...
six months, a year or more.
And it will give you an opportunity
to make arrangements .
You'd do that ?
Well, if you ask me, yes.
Why ?
Does there really need to be a reason ?
I was raised by my grandmother who taught me
that in matters of obligation, nothing comes free.
Well let's say that ... that I like you.
You and your husband.
And I'm sure this child will be happier
with you, and you with him.
So why you didn't you speak up
in front of Daniel, just now ?
Because he wouldn't have accepted the deal !
Yes.
You talk about a deal !
There's a condition ?
Yes. Silence!
Absolute.
You mustn't talk to anyone else about it. Ever !
But rest assured it's the only thing I ask of you.
Good. Do I make this phone call, or not.
Yes.
Darling!
Oh, my darling.
It's so good to feel you there.
You've nothing to say ?
You've been 'dead' for a month and a half !
Let me get used to it.
He passed for dead in order to escape.
We couldn't warn you. We've just crossed the goal line.
I'll not keep you any longer.
You won't stay for a bit ?
You know, without Monsieur Schwartz,
I could never have crossed the Line .
No, thank you.
That's kind. There's Jeannine waiting for me.
See you soon Marie.
Goodbye Monsieur Schwartz.
And thank you !
Thank you, Mr. Schwartz.
You know, in your profession. If they really dismiss
all the Jews, they'll eventually run out of people.
It will surely settle down.
How are you going to manage ?
Excuse me for disturbing you.
You're not disturbing us. I'm going.
Where are you going ?
I have just been dismissed in a fifteen line letter.
Not even a line for each year of seniority !
Why?
The 'Statute of Jews', Commissaire. Apparently
we no longer have the right to be civil servants.
I'm sorry, really.
Ah yes, I know, everyone is.
Thank you anyway.
Good. Lucienne.
It's okay, my girl, huh ?
Monsieur le Commissaire.
What are we going to do without her ?
Excuse me, what did you come to see us for ?
Yes. I wanted to contact Madame Morhange.
but now that she's ...
You know about the dead British pilot ?
Yes, like everyone.
We have to ensure his burial. The Germans will
bring his body to the school in a minute or two.
So, are you able to prepare him ?
Wash him, dress him.
I'll do my best.
Goodbye.
Thierry.
Goodbye Madame. Goodbye and good luck.
Madame Morhange !
I was wondering ... where are you going now ?
I don't know.
Tonight at the hotel. Tomorrow I'll
come to get my things.
And then I'll see... as I have a brother in Paris.
But I think I'd rather prefer the
Academic Inspector of the other day !
I may have a solution, perhaps.
Escoffier. You knew who he was ?
Yes. The guy who killed himself
after strangling his mistress.
Yes. He had two small rooms
right next to the Commissariat.
That's where he kept her. According to
the lawyer, the heirs are scrapping.
It could last for years. It's not bad,
it's furnished.
If you want it, it's yours.
Are you serious ?
Thank you.
It's kind of you to have thought of it.
But no. It's natural.
Darling?
Oh, it's Papa.
May I ?
Of course !
You look worried !
Madame Morhange has just been dismissed.
She was Jewish ?
Visibly, yes.
Well, you might be able to get him
some private lessons ?
Especially now, people are looking for that.
I strongly doubt she'd be interested.
In her place it wouldn't interest me.
Darling, do you think I am right to continue ?
But if you resign, who's going to replace you ?
You're generous, humane, you think
of the welfare of others, yes ...
Yes, Daniel, I think it's better if you go on.
I know this is hard for you,
but it's best for Villeneuve.
What do you think ?
As to Te Quiero, I've been thinking.
For months you and him have been my only joy.
I'm going to make an official request for adoption.
Ah, but haven't you seen Jean ?
No. I think he went out this evening.
In fact it was a mistake. The man you saw
this morning is not Te Quiero's father.
Not his father ?
Jean did not give me details. He just told me
that it was a mistake and we had nothing to fear ...
... and he told me he'd explain to you.
You can't know how happy I was.
There was a Prince of Orange.
Rose early in the morning.
Went to see his page
"Go saddle my steed"
"Curse this damned war"
My handsome Prince of Orange.
Where do you want to go ?
"Curse this damned war"
"Where would you go ?"
"I want to go to France"
"Where the King has summoned me"
"Curse this damned war"
"Set the hands to the reins"
"The feet in the stirrups"
"Curse this damned"
"Feet in the stirrups"
Subtitles by Rod Clarke
Whitby, Ont. February 2014