Numerous units of the German Navy are docked
in North Sea ports, the Channel and the Atlantic Coast.
Minesweepers accompany the formation.
And here, fast patrol boats.
...German Stukas of the sea.
Many powerful batteries of German coastal artillery...
...which dominate the Channel
All hands to battle.
An enemy convoy is subject to violent fire
from German guns.
The English coastline and Port of Dover
are continually bombarded
The southern extremity of the British coast
is entirely within range of the German guns.
It's cleaning time for German troops in France.
Antitank guns are cleaned...
Look. I'm going to the toilet.
Little streams are a good opportunity
to thoroughly clean these steel mastiffs.
BLACK MARKETS
Yes. You have friends in the area ?
OK !
I can't bear not seeing you, any longer.
Seeing each other won't help, only cause hurt.
I'm not made for a double life, Raymond.
Me neither.
During his stay in France, the Fuhrer
received Monsieur Laval the Foreign Minister,
and Maréchal Pétain.
The two French statesmen were given
full military honours.
I can't live without you.
Sarah, do you know the best ?
Monsieur and I decided to go
to the cinema at the last moment.
Well, do you know. The show was cancelled.
The hooligans began whistling the Maréchal.
They had to put the lights on in the hall.
There was a scuffle. It was ridiculous.
Actually, have you mended my blue jacket ?
It's getting cold.
No. I haven't had time, Madame.
It's OK, thank you.
Not had time !
Not had the time. She's impertinent, that girl !
She's young.
When I was young, I knew how to conduct myself.
Obviously the wine is bad for your memory.
No, but I don't know...
...you saw how she talks to me.
Did you see how she looks at me.
I feel no respect.
You're right. I'll talk to her.
You're making soup ?
You know, about just now...
If Madame finds out I was
at the cinema, she'll sack me.
You didn't see me or anything, right ?
Monsieur, I saw nothing...
...since I wasn't there !
So ?
Kommandant, what do you want us to do
about the kids whistling in the cinema ?
They're not kids. By chance there was
a Sicherheitdienst man in the hall...
...he said he saw a leader
who stood at the back of the hall...
...and shouted slogans.
Your Policeman couldn't identify this leader ?
No. He was in the company of a lady.
But he's going to make a report to Besançon.
And from tomorrow, I'm going to take tougher measures.
We're really abashed, Kommandant.
Send your superiors our most
sincere apologies for this incident.
I don't care about your excuses.
What are you going to do about
this outrage against public order ?
I assure you that we'll investigate.
Our Police will do their job.
In Germany the police control agitators.
In Germany, no-one dare whistle the Führer in a cinema.
No way will you write a letter
to the Maréchal.
Why ? All my friends are doing one.
Well, all the more reason not to.
But what am I going to say to the Mistress ?
Just tell her you have no ideas.
But it's true that I've no ideas.
That's why I'm asking you to help me.
You're not to write a letter.
It's a matter of principle.
What's a principle ?
Well, it's...
OK, little guy, until tonight.
See you tonight, Papa.
I recognize you !
Police!
Police. This guy put Bolshevik
leaflets in letterboxes.
Stop !
Give them to me. Quick.
Oh! You should be more be careful.
Messieurs.
You didn't stop when a policeman whistled you ?
I was scared. It's idiotic, I know.
Let me see your bag.
Strange to have a bag with nothing in it.
I took my son to school. His things were in it.
Good, It's OK. Go on. Move on.
We're not going looking for a kid who
whistled in a cinema. It's ridiculous.
We're not asking your opinion Commissaire.
We're asking you to do the job you're paid for.
And if he is found, we hand him
over to the Boches ? Like Marek !
You know Marek got 10 years hard labour.
Wait. We shouldn't look for the one who
whistled, or it's impossible to do it ?
Because it's not the same.
Finding a kid who whistled
in the dark is impossible.
It's perfectly possible.
Dijon Intelligence have done it several times.
Just a bit pressure on those nearby
and witnesses. It's possible.
Ah, we're getting somewhere.
Right. Witnesses, neigbours, pressure.
The Germans are furious. We must do something.
Monsieur le Sous-Préfet.
It's out of the question that the perpetrator
be taken by the Germans this time.
If we find him, we'll judge him.
It remains between Frenchmen.
Listen, we'll do our best.
I want better than that.
I need your word, Monsieur le Sous-Préfet.
My word !
Yes, or else you'll have
my resignation on your desk...
...tomorrow morning.
All right. I'll confirm it with Besançon.
Anyway, I'm sure if we find the leader
the Fritz will be content.
You have my word.
Make this word stand for something.
I'm taking a risk here. Don't disappoint me.
Shit, this guy still whistled at the Maréchal.
And Hitler.
De Kervern, the Maréchal is all we have today.
It doesn't please me that the Maréchal
shakes hands with Hitler.
But I assume he knows what he's doing.
Good. I'm counting on you.
In theory there are only 48 hours.
Gentlemen !
What are you up to ?
I'm only telling the truth. That's all.
Stop bullshitting me with the truth.
I'm not a kid.
The truth !
I'm asking you not to conduct this investigation.
And the Mayor, who's our superior
has just asked us to lead it.
So maybe I should go back and ask him
for confirmation of this order ?
You're on the way to losing your soul, my son.
And you, Gustave, have you started your letter ?
No, Mistress, not yet.
I can hardly hear you, Gustave.
No, Mistress, I haven't started it.
I have no ideas.
I don't know the Maréchal.
How can I write to him ?
How can I, if I don't know the Maréchal ?
We all know the Maréchal.
What did the Maréchal do children ?
He made a gift of his person to France.
Very good. Have you asked your Papa to help you ?
A Papa always has good ideas.
Er...      No, I forgot.
You must tell him.
Tell him that next Monday we are going to read
all the letters before the Academic Inspector.
And if you haven't done your letter, I'll have to
speak to the new Headmaster, Monsieur Bériot.
He'll not be at all happy.
Did you understand ?
Yes Mistress.
Yes. Good. Sit down.
Where can we talk ? At the café ?
Certainly not.
In the Post Office ?
Oh no, I prefer not.
There's a cleaning lady,
I don't know what time she arrives.
Wait for me in the courtyard there.
I'll go through the main entrance.
I really wanted to thank you for just now.
It wasn't a big thing.
Even so. It was prison if they'd found them on me.
...or on you.
How did you know ?
Where did you put them ?
Well, I burned them.
Sorry! But I couldn't take the risk
of someone stumbling on them in the office.
Frankly... to take risks like that for such nonsense !
Against the profiteers of London and Vichy.
Join the Communists...
...have you nothing else to say to people ?
You're for the Profiteers ?
No.
But to put London and Vichy in the same class. It's....
...I can't find the right word.
.. its Communist !
Is it the cleaning lady ?
No, she doesn't have keys to the back door.
Listen. I'm ready to do something.
Monday is the 11th of November.
It will be an opportunity...
I've an idea for massively distributing a flyer...
...but we have to call a spade a spade.
Meaning ?
The Boches              Out with them.
I don't know. I'll have to talk to the Comrades.
I'm Marcel Larcher.
Suzanne Richard.
Where were you in the hall ?
In the sixth Row.
In the centre.
Always in the centre, Inspecteur.
And when there was the noise, did you turn ?
Obviously. But I didn't see who whistled.
But you saw people.
Towards the last row.
Vaguely.
Can you give me their names.
That way, they can tell us who whistled.
I didn't have a good view, you know.
Listen Monsieur Camille, I haven't all day.
I need to find names. And unfortunately
if you don't give me any I'll be forced
to believe it was you who whistled.
Oh ! I wouldn't have the courage.
I remember...in the last row
there was the little Schwartz maid...
Sarah.
It surprised me because Monday's her day off, so...
...I wondered how she'd arranged
to be at the cinema on a Sunday.
And she whistled ?
No. I think she was, well...
perhaps she was with those who whistled...
...but I'm not sure of it.
In any case she didn't whistle.
I say, I wouldn't like to hurt little Sarah.
She's really nice for a Jew.
Sarah isn't here ?
It's Monday.
It tires me thinking about caulking windows.
Couldn't she do it before leaving ?
You only have to ask.
Good evening Monsieur Schwartz.
Inspecteur ?
Please come in.
Thank you.
I'm sorry to bother you.
It is about your servant, Sarah Meyer.
She's not here. I believe.
No. This is her half day off.
That's what they said. Madame.
Monsieur.
Would you have seen her at the cinema,
at the Mairie, last night ?
Certainly not. During her work hours !
You're sure ?
Obviously !
Moreover, we were there.
Oh good !
And when they whistled, did you see anything ?
Oh no. I was in the toilet.
When I came back, the room was all lit up...
...and the agitators were gone, I believe.
Good! And you ?
I was watching the screen,
and afterwards I didn't see very much.
But you have reason to think
Sarah was at the cinema yesterday ?
Sorry. I can't tell you any more.
Can you ask her to come to the Commissariat,
first thing in the morning ?
Of course.
Very well.
Sorry for the inconvenience.
Good evening.
He seems to think that Sarah was at the cinema yesterday.
If she's done such a thing I'll give her a weeks notice.
We would have seen her!
Say it. We would have seen her all the same !
Obviously, yes.
Raymond ?
You saw her at the cinema yesterday ?
No.
Tell me the truth.
Wait, Jeanine, what are you talking about ?
When you went to the toilet it lasted far too long.
You went to find her.
You've made Sarah your mistress.
You're crazy.
Sarah !
Swear on Marceau's head.
Sarah's not your mistress.
Jeanine!
Swear it.
I swear on the Marceau's head
that Sarah's not my mistress.
Going OK ?
No.
I've redone the accounts.
They don't work out.
Oh...You're exaggerating.
We been indebted for many years.
We are far from being in debt. In any event, my
parents, my grandparents always were.
There's something wrong.
You didn't pay rent to Monsieur Schwartz
for the last quarter ?
Yes. In fact...
The bank was closed during the refugee exodus.
It was complicated. I was....
...unable to pay it. I've arranged it with him.
Arranged ?
How ?
You know he's a rich employer.
He told me to pay when I could pay...
when everything's back in order.
Well, everything is back in order.
I came back.
Yes.
...but I couldn't have imagined.
Did he say about the interest ?
No. In fact, he told me you two would talk about it.
Sarah.
It's Monsieur Schwartz.
Sarah, open the door.
It'll only take a few minutes.
I want to talk to you.
I can't just now.
Listen, the Police came to question me about you last night.
Open it for me.
No ! Are you crazy Sarah ?
If Madame had caught you ?
It's not what you think.
I was forced to sleep here.
Aren't you Bellini's son ?
You won't talk to Madame ?
Listen, I'm not here. You weren't at the cinema.
Agree ?
But you say that the Police came.
Is it about the Jewish Census ?
No. They came to investigate
the incident at the cinema yesterday.
They want you at the Commissariat this morning.
But what to do ?
I was just about to ask that question.
You were with her at the cinema ?
And so ?
It was you who whistled.
It doesn't concern me.
...but I told them you weren't at the cinema.
So don't go contradicting me.
Are you crazy, or what ?
Your Head Post Mistress is Suzanne Richard,
the wife of Lucien Richard
The guy of the SFIO. The French Section
of the Workers International !
You made a deal with a Social-Fascist traitor, Comrade.
You're exaggerating. She saved the situation.
Exactly !
That's what's suspicious.
First, she saves the situation,
and then, afterwards, like....
Afterwards, by chance, she proposes an action.
It smells like a clear police provocation...
You must cease all contact with her immediately.
I feel she's sincere.
As for the idea of organising an action
on November 11th, the Party will have nothing
to do patriotic celebrations.
Moreover, it doesn't surprise me that
a Social-Fascist traitor would want
to enroll you in this kind of behaviour...
...anti-Party.
At our next meeting, I expect self-criticism
in good and due form from you, Comrade.
You've just proved that you poorly appreciate
the Party's strategic position at a crucial time.
I'll have to make a report
to the Interregional Committee.
And I don't want to hear any more
of this action on November 11th.
Good day Mademoiselle.
Inspecteur.
Please, sit down.
Don't worry. I'm seeing you
just as a matter of routine.
Ah good.
Can you tell me about your Sunday afternoon ?
What were you doing ?
Well...what time ?
Let's say between 6pm and 8pm.
Well, my employers, Monsieur and Madame Schwartz
had gone to the cinema...
I darned socks, caulked windows...
...that's it.
But all that doesn't take two hours.
There were lots of socks perhaps.
I prepared dinner of course.
And then, but you mustn't tell Madame Schwartz,
I was reading.
A novel. Do you know Martin Eden ?
No. I never read.
...apart from police reports.
Do you know Camille Hutzinger ?
Yes, a little.
He says that he knows you well.
He loves you too.
She often lets me have her place in queues,
and is nice for a Jew.
He was at the cinema on Sunday.
He placed you there, while you were reading...
Martin Eden.
There you are !
He said he recognized you.
Near the last row.
He has poor eyesight.
He knows you.
Which compensates for that.
I tell you I didn't go out yesterday.
The cashier remembers you.
She thinks you weren't alone,
but she didn't see who you were with.
Listen, Sarah...
You're Jewish.
You didn't identify yourself in the Census.
You went to the cinema, fooling your boss.
You lied to the Police.
You're in bad trouble here.
So help me to help you.
It's not worth losing your place with the Schwartz,
Your peace of mind, maybe even your freedom.
Sarah, you were in the cinema on Sunday.
Yes or no ?
Yes.
With a man ?
But he didn't whistle !
I swear it.
No. No. I understand. I believe you.
Just give me his name.
So that he can confirm your testimony.
It's only matter of routine.
Michel...Michel Bellini.
Son of the President of the Chamber of Commerce ?
I can't get to work!
I hitched up the ox...
...and I said to myself, what use is it all ?
I don't understand you.
You've never thought like this before.
But since then, there's been a war, Marie.
All for what ?
Hey, you've moved the chest.
Yes. Don't you think it makes more space ?
How did you move it ?
That chest is heavy !
Some cattle dealers who came to take the sheep.
One of them helped me.
They came on the stroke of eleven.
It's true it weighs a lot.
Which one ?
Which of the cattle merchants helped you ?
Alibert.
That poor guy. He was killed in a
bombing raid at the end of May. Didn't I tell you ?
Poor Alibert !
All these guys croaked for nothing !
Wasn't Alibert re-repatriated ?
I saw him limping when I left.
How are you Monsieur Germain.
Good day.
What do you want ?
Ah well. I'm here for the monthly Requisition.
Didn't you read the letters we sent you ?
I told you about it.
Why can't you leave us with what we have.
We need to give you something more ? Is that it?
A horse and a pig.
A horse and a pig. You don't want my wife as well ?
Laurin !
Monsieur Germain it's not personal,
it's a question of solidarity...
...with those who have nothing.
And if I give you my horse...
...I will have less to care for.
And if I have less to care for, in the spring
there'll be nothing left to requisition.
Laurin !
It is not me that makes up the rules and quotas.
Ah that's it. It's not you. It's not you....
It's never anyone, eh ?
But you take a commission, right ?
Well, in the past it's been normal !
In the past.
I'm going to knock you into the past, I am.
Bastard.
No. Stop it!
Go on. Get out !
Get out.
That bastard won't come near again.
It's not him who'll come back,
if you carry on like this, it's the Gendarmes.
What's your plan for November 11th ?
You've spoken to the Comrades ?
Yes.
And what did they say ?
I'll tell you when you've told me about your plan.
You're not a joker ?
No.
My plan is to shower Villeneuve
with flyers like this one.
...on which you can write whatever you like.
Getting them delivered
along with 'The Villeneuvois'.
There are 1500 subscribers.
Around 4 am, the papers are left
in front of the Sayolle depot.
I pick them up every other week.
On Monday the 11th it's my turn.
If I make a detour between here and Sayolle,
there's an hour to slide them under the wrappers.
Afterwards, I carry them here.
And 2 hours later, 1,500 Villeneuvois
have their flyer with breakfast.
But the cops will figure out
immediately where they came from.
Hello, Madame Morvandieu.
Good day.
She's a work colleague, and she's very nice.
There's nothing to be afraid of.
We need to find another place for a rendezvous.
But where ?
We'll see.
How are you going to do it so the cops don't
figure out straight away how it was done ?
The papers lie in front of the
Sayolles depot for 2 hours unattended.
Anyone can come and slide stuff in !
Aren't there people who sleep near the depot ?
It's absolutely deserted.
The Boches and cops aren't far ?
No.
The Comrades told me I should
cease all contact with you.
But I want to do something.
I think your plan could work.
I'm sure of it.
When you talked to me of a meal tête à tête,
I imagined a place more...
Yes, but I'm constantly on duty.
My colleague is obsessed with
his cinema investigation, so...
They should decorate those who whistled !
Let's not exaggerate.
It's not good ?
Yes, yes it's delicious.
Did you find it on the black market.
Oh, no. I don't buy anything
on the black market. Really
I only arrest those who do.
Are you serious ?
Never completely. No.
So, you're OK in the strangler's flat ?
Do you want to give me nightmares.
And the job ?
It is a substitute, sewing.
First, because I'm not as good
as I thought, and especially...
I didn't think that dozens of women
would have the same idea as me.
You know how to type ?
Yes.
I need a part-time Assistant.
Madame Sabourin is going to leave us
to join her family in the Lot.
You know, I haven't ceased being
Jewish after three weeks.
But this is a contract position for one year.
The Statute of Jews doesn't apply to contractors.
Why are you doing this for me, Commissaire ?
Henri.
Why are you doing this for me, Henri ?
I wanted to ask you something...
Henri ?
Henri !
Do you think I should
register myself as Jewish or not ?
Yes. You should do it.
It'll save you troubles.
And now they've revoked you,
what more do you risk ?
How's it going ?
It's not. No.
We still have problems with the last Fritz order.
Ah, they pay well, but they're so boring.
With them, it's simple, things never go well.
Perhaps that's how they won the war.
By the way, the Mayor of Essart called.
It seems there's a problem with the tenants.
What problem ?
Something about a Requisition. I think Laurin
was raving. He even waved his gun at them.
No-one was injured ?
No.
But the Mayor plans to send the Gendarmes.
You may need to think of getting him out.
Wait...
OK, I'll go and see them tomorrow.
Very good.
Laurin isn't here ?
He's in the top field. He'll have heard the car.
He won't be long.
Don't worry. We wont talk about that.
What's happened ?
Laurin isn't the same since he returned.
I went to see the Mayor of Essart. It's fixed.
He calmed down when he realized
that I worked for the Wehrmacht.
You always do that !
You got rid of the gun ?
Yes, but we must talk about the rents.
Rents ?
Ah, Monsieur Schwartz !
Glad to see you.
Likewise.
Hey, you need to cool things
a little there with Garnier.
Ah, that's OK. I've already had
a lecture from the boss.
Say, without wanting to trouble you...
...I'd like you to give me a hand.
There's a pig to dress.
It's easier with three.
Go on. Marie !
Go and get the bucket.
That's good.
Bring the bucket here.
Come on, let's go.
You know what, Monsieur Schwartz.
When I go away with Marie...
I need you, Laurin.
You're the best tenant I ever had.
Look out.
With the Requisitions, the debts,
all that, we have to go Monsieur Schwartz.
With all the money we owe you !
Money, what money ?
The rents.
Yes, the rents and well...
You told me you'd arrange with Laurin
about the interest on what we owe you.
Don't worry, I'm in no hurry.
But what interest rate will you charge.
That's what worries us.
Right, listen, I don't know.
All I know is that...
I know a way you can earn not bad money.
I don't see how.
Well, your pig...
It's an average one.
I'll only get 20 francs maximum at the Salins Market
Yes. Well I'll go see a worker who's
marrying off his daughter on Sunday.
I can get 1,000 francs minimum.
Hello,Raymond.
Good day, are you well ?
It's okay, you can go.
And, Good day.
Good Evening Herr Schwartz.
So, how was your Leave ?
Very good but not long enough.
Too short.
Ja, short.
And Greta and the children are well ?
Ja, they would like me to return home.
Ah, yes. Can I go now ?
Ja.
Ah, but wait, Greta gave me a present. I'll show you.
Kom Willie! Kom hop-hop!
This is Willie.
Say hello to Monsieur Schwartz.
Oh yes, yes. Very beautiful !
Willie ?
He's not stupid.
Herr Schwartz, are you carrying something ?
Her Schwartz ?
A side of pork for sauerkraut, interested in some ?
Herr Schwartz !
And how would you still have wine like this ?
It's extraordinary.
Isn't it very expensive ?
It's true it's not bad.
We still have a good cellar.
You were telling me that you had news ?
The Fritz are becoming unbearable.
It's Inspecteur Marchetti that has the news.
Well, I actually identified a suspect.
Formidable ! He admits the facts ?
Well I don't know that as yet. Commissaire
de Kervern doesn't want me to interview him.
What does he mean by that ?
He wasn't sober for the whole of June...
Is he a Freemason or not ?
Anyway, the guy is brave man
and a good Commissaire.
Yes, but what we need today
are brave men with a nuance.
You're going to arrest this suspect.
I'll give you a written order.
Very good.
What's he called ?
Michel Bellini.
They were surely other persons whistling ?
Maybe.
But I think Bellini is the ring leader
we're looking for.
Well, you can interview him but not arrest him.
May I know why Monsieur Sous-Préfet ?
Inspecteur !
Let it go.
I know the Bellini father personally,
but that's not the problem.
He's a notable. If you arrest his son,
you arrest an enemy of Public Order.
But at the same time...
...you undermine the good society
which is a basis of Public Order.
Do you understand ?
Let me take care of the child.
Don't get me wrong,
but I'm not totally in agreement with you.
Do you know why Pétain's
Montoire agreement is going wrong ?
Because everything's going wrong,
The prisoners of war aren't returning.
Provisions are scarce.
The Germans are going to stay,
for how long we don't know.
The Maréchal shook Hitler's hand,
and no-one even knows why.
To stall for time, obviously. It's a ruse.
Let him continue.
If we want to get the spirit of Montoire
across to people, here's the message...
We need to get it across
to the people of Villeneuve today.
We're going to make Order prevail
without distinction of wealth...
...birth, class, or anything...
...just Order. If you let the son of a notable
go scot-free, it will put us back six months.
He's dead right.
Very good. You've convinced me.
You have carte blanche.
Thank you.
So is Montoire going so badly ?
It's true people don't understand it.
To meet with Hitler, that's one thing.
But to shake his hand !
That was really clumsy, I'm sorry.
I apologize.
These political lunches don't bore you too much ?
No more than you.
Will you pour me one ?
Thank you.
What is that.
Are you in the black market Raymond ?
I'm helping Marie and Laurin
who are a bit strapped right now.
Ah, you're helping Marie and Laurin...
Marie...and Laurin...
That's good...we should help people.
You know I was scared yesterday.
Stamler had brought a dog from Dusseldorf.
The dog smelled the meat.
It was lucky that von Ritter
wanted a real sauerkraut, or else...
Besides, it would be nice to pack
the pieces to sell to Lévrier.
What portion is this ?
Is it the shoulder ?
What do you take it for ?
What do I take it for ?
You ask me what I take it for.
You, going to smooch with your mistress
in the cinema toilet !
What are you talking about ?
Oh, fine. Sarah told me everything.
She came back from the Commissariat in tears.
She was with her boyfriend at the cinema...
...and everything else.
You're making that into a wrong I did to you ?
...a wrong you did to me, to me...
.. and Marceau and Papa.
If Papa knew that.
I don't know who told you this,
but it's completely false.
That's just going on lying...
Stop it ! Shut up.
You stop !
Stop it.
If you don't get rid of her I'll tell Papa,
and you can say goodbye to your factory.
And your son at the same time.
Jeannine, I want you to calm down.
Madame. Madame...
My parents have written about
the Jewish Census and...
.. they say I have to go there.
If you want to go, Sarah, go ahead...
Yes, but the deadline is today.
Oh no, you not going to miss
another half day's work.
That's enough.
You'll have to go during your day off.
It will be near enough for a Jewess !
Leave us.
I want you to get rid of this slut,
do you hear me ?
I want you to get rid of her.
You're happy.
Yes. But you should be happy too.
The Germans are renouncing any sanctions,
and have confirmed to Servier that...
...they'll let our Judges deal with the case.
It's worse.
Hold on. I'm not following you there.
Yes. I know.
Where were you on Sunday at 6 pm ?
At the cinema.
Do you remember when people whistled ?
You're saying that I whistled ?
Wait...you admit the facts ?
I didn't know it was forbidden
to whistle in cinemas.
It's forbidden to whistle at the Maréchal.
It was Hitler that I whistled at.
It's not my fault that he was
shaking hands with Pétain.
Go on, empty your pockets on the desktop.
What's this ?
An address book.
...with lots of girl's first names.
You speak Spanish ?
No.
It's something I found on a corpse at the church.
I thought she no longer needed it.
Did you read this ?
I told you, I don't speak Spanish.
It's not pretty to loot the dead.
I didn't loot it, they were taking her
to the common grave.
Now listen, you made a big mistake
whistling at the Maréchal.
But OK. You're young, so this time,
we'll let you go.
But don't try it again.
Because next time, it'll cost you very dearly.
Do you understand that ?
I'm keeping this.
Now its me who doesn't understand you.
Well, it'll be a pleasure for the Sous-Préfet.
Ah, Inspecteur.
It seems you've released little Bellini.
I just dressed him down a bit.
The Germans were glad we'd found him, and then...
...I said to myself that we shouldn't
go too hard so as to please the Sous-Préfet.
You'll go far, Marchetti.
I'll leave you.
I haven't finished my consultations.
Go ahead please.
Madame Larcher ?
I have something for you.
For me ?
Yes.
Take this.
It belonged to the woman
who gave birth to Te Quiero.
I found it during an investigation.
It's her. He has her eyes.
Yes.
Thank you !
Subtitles by Rod Clarke.
Whitby, Ontario. Feb 2014