CHAOS
Please stop.
Daniel look, he looks like your nephew.
Gustave ?
Uncle !
You're all alone ?
Where are your parents ?
I don't know, I haven't seen them
since the day of the aeroplane.
You've been all alone since that time ?
I slept in the woods, there were wild animals
but they didn't harm me.
Why didn't you come home ?
I came yesterday but there was no-one there.
Just a big hole in the wall.
Perhaps they're injured !
No. They must have done like us.
Left and then returned.
We're going to find them.
I can't do more, Raymond.
We can't continue living crowded like this.
What do you want me to do ?
Where are you going.
To take a powder, I've a headache.
I'm getting something from the dining room.
I'm in my own home, aren't I ?
.
You haven't found the aspirin ?
I'd forgotten, there isn't any left.
I'd like a mint bonbon.
.
Madame, Madame, I've only found
sausage, eggs and a little milk.
The bread is a bit dry, it needs dampening.
Shall I put it all in the kitchen ?
.
No, no. In the bedroom as we only have that room !
What news of the farm. Have you seen Marie ?
No, no-one has seen her for a week.
Since the presence of ... She took her children then...
.
She should have warned us !
Old Georges is looking after the animals.
As for housing problems, due to the presence of...
...apparently there's an office
at the church where they take care of it.
I'm going to try and see if I can get them out of here.
Hello Docteur Larcher.
What's happening Pierrot ?
It's been jammed for hours, you can't get through.
Go and see.
Don't move.
Good day Henri.
Good day Docteur.
Good day.
We can't get through.
I'm looking after it, Madame.
Halt !
Good day.
I'm Docteur Larcher,
Deputy to the Mayor of Villeneuve.
I'm returning home with my family. The people
on the bridge are all from the town. I'll vouch for them.
What do they want of you ?
Not the cart. No vehicles in the town.
Follow the soldier, Docteur.
First of all I want to go home.
Follow the soldier.
Wait here.
Where are all the people ?
Don't look.
Why did they do that ?
He was almost certainly a robber, a looter.
Follow me !
Herr Kommandant, this is Docteur Larcher.
You're Docteur Larcher ?
Yes.
For two days I've looked for someone
who can speak for the town.
But I'm only the Mayor's Deputy, I can't speak for the town.
It's me who decides who can and can't speak, Docteur.
I need...
For two days they've repeatedly fired on German Forces.
And that's inadmissible.
It seems to come from the church
where all sorts of people are crammed.
I'm giving you until this evening
to take things in hand, Docteur.
How do you...
I consider you and your family
as hostages, so that you take responsibility.
Your life depends on what happens
to German troops in this town.
Is that clear ?
Is that clear, Docteur ?
Do you have your insulin, Madame Verdier ?
Yes thank you very much, Docteur Larcher.
Come on, Gustave. Let's go.
Docteur Larcher....Docteur Larcher.
My daughter's very, very ill.
Since the bombing my wife has an earache.
She can hardly hear anything.
Go ahead. I'll get back to you right away.
Docteur ! Docteur !
Docteur Larcher !
It's my wife.
I'll come in a moment, Madame.
Come on, Gustave.
Hortense...
We need to leave here.
But the Germans say we're hostage.
We simply need to avoid the main street.
We'll take the ambulance. With the reserve of petrol
we can reach Geneva at least.
And Gustave ?
Gustave ? We'll take him with us !
Docteur !
Inspector Marchetti. We saw each other
two weeks ago at Schwartz's mill.
You were delivering a baby. Remember ?
My wife.
It's absolute chaos, eh ?
The priest was killed by a stray bullet last week.
And the Mayor ?
Evaporated. I sent messages to all the deputies and...
It's good you're here.
And de Kervern ?
I don't know. Oh yes I do know.
I saw him just now. He was dead drunk.
What do all these people want ?
They're wounded, sick and homeless.
Many refugees.
I tried to get as many as possible to leave.
But there's nothing doing.
What do we do ?
You should go and get milk for Te Quiero.
There's an infirmary ?
Yes. We've got a resourceful girl
making dressings in the Sacristry.
And we had Docteur Moret.
He left last night.
He was supposed to return this morning.
But he hasn't come.
Maman ! Maman.
Gustave !
My darling, my love.
There you are ! Oh, my darling.
Where were you ? We searched everywhere, everywhere.
I was dying with worry.
We found him by the bridge
That was sheer luck !
We'd stopped hoping.
Excuse me. I've no milk and my baby
hasn't been fed since this morning.
If you could... Just a few sips,
if you can spare a little
Yes. Of course. Give him to me.
Thank you.
Come on sweetie.
There. I'll put your little cover on like that....
...all wrapped up.
You're going to be warm.
Are you hungry ?
Is this child yours ?
No, it's Madame's...
Yes... They gave him to me. I'm watching
him until they find his family.
Yes, but the Red Cross has asked us
to collect lost children.
It's better if I look after him.
That's good. Has he taken any food ?
Yes he's had a little.
No. wait...
He hasn't had his feed.
Yes, I'm used to that.
Come with me, we need to do the paperwork.
Aunty Hortense has a baby.
A baby ?
A refugee child.
Gustave told me there's a hole in your house.
I'm afraid the north wall will collapse.
They say there's a centre for re-housing.
You won't mind if I examine you for two minutes ?
She saw Docteur Moret yesterday.
He said that she just needed to rest.
You've got thinner since I saw you at Norbert's wedding.
A little, yes.
Does it amuse you to frighten us. Is that it ?
Listen, Marcel. You know we never agree on anything.
We agree on the fact that she's sick
and I'm a Doctor.
You need to get out of here. This air is stale.
Don't you feel it ? For her it's much worse.
She's at risk of respiratory failure.
Moret said that he was coming by
this evening to give her asthma medicine.
Marcel...
I trust Moret.
He didn't leave when people were in the shit !
But for the little one, thanks with all my heart.
Calm down. Return to your places.
Everyone calm down.
Get back to what you were doing.
It's nothing.
Docteur...some guys were arguing.
They were shooting at each other.
It's not serious but people are on edge.
They can't help screaming over anything.
We absolutely must retrieve all weapons.
Yes. Together.
The German Kommandant says I'm responsible,
and me and my family are hostages for it.
I'm responsible to see that the German
troops don't come here. Understand ?
If we have to disarm, we'll disarm them. Come on !
You know how to use that ?
No.
Good for there aren't any cartridges.
Listen, put it in your pocket and hold it tight.
It'll give you courage. If there's a commotion,
get it out. Generally it dissuades them. OK ?
I'm not sure I'm the right one for this.
Docteur, you're probably not the right
person but it looks like you're the only one.
Take it.
Come on !
Excuse me. Are you from Les Essarts ?
Yes.
Do you know Marie Germain, Lorrain the farmer's wife?
Vaguely.
Have you seen her in the last 10 days ?
No. There was quite a lot
of sniping at Les Essarts.
I believe there's a list of the missing or dead...
...in the tent down there.
Sit there Monsieur.
Take that off.
Marie ?
How are you ?
Getting along.
I thought I was going mad after the other day.
I had no news !
I went by the farm yesterday evening.
I was really worried.
I left to take the kids to my Mother's,
and I was stuck on the way back.
I was terrified of never seeing you again.
How did you end up here ?
I came to look for news of Lorrain.
And then Docteur Moret asked for a volunteer
for an hour or two...
... that was yesterday noon.
So... Lorrain?
Nothing.
His unit had to retreat to Reims.
I think of you all the time, after the other day.
Monsieur Schwartz you must forget what happened.
You know it !
Really.
Good day.
I'm the Deputy Mayor, with full police powers.
Give me your weapons please.
It's wartime. Civilians are forbidden to carry arms.
If you please.
No. Leave it in its case.
It's real leather. English. It's worth a lot.
Here you are.
Here you are, Docteur.
Thank you.
Is this one of little Michaël?
Let me have it. At the funeral his mother
asked me to get it back.
What courage that woman !
She said she was praying for you.
On the other hand the Schwartz woman
appears to want to file a complaint.
I believe that little Marceau is doing OK ?
Yes....yes.
But she won't want to let it rest there.
And this complaint is... ?
Is it against the school or me ?
It doesn't much matter. In either case the
administration will lay it on you.
I couldn't have imagined that... that Bruno...
That Monsieur Fournier hadn't filled in
the proper documents.
Messieurs ?
Feldwebel Wagner.
By order of Kreiskommandant Von Ritter, I'm here
to requisition the boy's school for the German Army.
Really ! And where will we put the boy's school ?
I don't know, Madame.
Do you have a written order, a paper or something ?
No, Madame.
I'm going to need all the keys, floor plans
state of repair and supplies, in duplicate.
I know the Germans. If there's no written
order it can still be avoided.
Go and find the Mayor. It seems there's
an emergency centre at the church.
Ask him if he can find anywhere else
for the Germans. Go on I'm counting on you.
Good day, Messieurs.
Docteur Larcher,
Deputy to the Mayor, and with Police Powers.
Yes, I remember. It was you who
delivered Handa and Yacin's daughter.
Did she finally come out of it ?
I don't know.
You have to give me any weapons you have.
We don't have any weapons here.
Listen you have a dagger,
him a revolver and him a rifle.
We've nothing against you.
We're collecting everyone's arms.
These are troubled times Docteur,
we don't know what could happen.
What will happen to you is big trouble
if you don't give me your weapons.
You don't think there's enough disorder ?
You want to add to the disorder and misery ?
Exactly...it's for safety Docteur.
Give me your weapons, you can't do otherwise.
You didn't listen to the doctor. Stand back.
You're not only shit stirring
with this crazy propaganda.
...but on top of that you're not listening
when a policeman gives you an order.
Drop your weapons.
Do it now !
Wait....give up your weapons,
we'll forget your names, and leave you in peace.
We're all victims, and not going to kill each other.
Docteur we need morphine for our two wounded.
Have you any ?
If you give up your weapons, and I find some morphine...
... I promise you'll be supplied first.
Doctor's Oath ?
Doctor's Oath
Give up your weapons.
Take this.
Right.
We've another big problem.
The girl at the nursing station says
there's risk of a dysentery epidemic.
Good. I'm going there.
Good day. I'm Docteur Larcher.
Is it you who spoke of dysentery ?
Yes. I'm only repeating what Dr Moret said.
You're a nurse
No. But I might as well be.
I've assisted Dr Moret since yesterday.
Take this.
Some patients have really severe diarrhea, Docteur.
There are 5 cases of dysentery and
one intestinal occlusion that needs an operation.
What sort of stuff has Moret left ?
... a box of sulfonamides,
Eight tablets left...
Good day Docteur. I'm Camille.
I think I've got a splinter in my throat.
Let me look, Monsieur.
Good day Mademoiselle, I need to telephone.
You've a telephone here ?
Please leave Monsieur, this is a medical area.
There's one in the Presbytery I think, Monsieur.
We need to screen people entering.
I'm afraid we'll be overwhelmed quickly.
We need compresses and bandages.
Yes. I sent Monsieur Schwartz to look
for linen, everything he could collect.
What did he want ?
I don't know.
What we absolutely need to find, are sulfonamides.
How many left ?
Eight. Dr Moret searched both town pharmacies.
They're empty.
Docteur, I've had trouble finding you.
We have a big problem at the school.
What now ?
The Germans have seized the school to make a barracks.
School starts in two months.
What do you want me to do ?
You're surely can't let the Germans
install themselves in our school !
Mademoiselle here are the sick. They're infected
and dying. Right now your problems aren't...
Do you want to be truly useful to the
population of Villeneuve ?
Of course.
Right ! Go to front of the waiting area and screen
the patients. If anyone asks for me, say I'm not here.
Don't let anyone in except my wife.
You know her ?
Yes.
And then start files for each patient,
with their name and problem.
Then make labels. Numbered labels.
Where can I find them ?
Do what you can, Mademoiselle.
Take paper, fold it and add a number.
If they bring you a body, put a label on the toes.
Then make armbands. Give some to the young
girl with me, to Monsieur Schwartz...
.....if he returns, to the Inspecteur,
and to my wife if you see her.
Screen the patients. Don't let anyone in.
No-one !
Please can I help with the screening Docteur.
Not in your state Monsieur.
I was an accountant in the past you know.
You need to hold his head up.
So... you have a date.
Yes, the 12th of June.
Was he dressed like that ?
No, those were bought in Besançon.
No bracelet or distinguishing mark ?
No.
His first name ?
Te Quiero.
Te Quiero ? He's Spanish ?
I don't know. Perhaps.
That's not a proper name. It means "I love you"
in Spanish. Te Quiero...I love you !
Is there no cradle free ?
No.
Ah well, put two in the same one.
For a few hours.
Where are you going to take him ?
A van should be here to take the children today.
Normally.
Otherwise we'll advise that they be
taken to the orphanage at Lons.
Come here, Sister !
This other kid looks strange !
It has diarrhea.
Couldn't you warn me sooner ?
Can I cover him up ?
Yes.
Is the doctor here ?
Yes, but...
He has terrible diarrhea.
Docteur, he has terrible diarrhea.
Why didn't you bring him sooner ?
We've just noticed.
I'm sorry. It's over.
At this age.....bloody diarrhea...
You're looking after other children ?
Yes.
Take these two tablets,
and mix them in a glass of water.
Give them a little spoonful for each 5kg weight.
Thank you.
Good luck.
If we do nothing they'll die like flies.
We need to record the numbers affected.
Segregate and isolate them.
And then get the bodies out !
They're extending the graves in the garden.
I'm going to find volunteers.
Does the Presbytery phone still work ?
When it wants to !
Call the Préfecture.
He's a good guy. He's surely stayed at his post.
Tell him people are dying here. That we
need food and drugs, especially sulfonamides.
And....fresh water, blankets and first aid kits.
Go on !
Germont, I'm going to need you.
Inspecteur, we need to get rid of the bodies.
We can't leave them like this, for all to see.
Very good Docteur.
Docteur ! You're Docteur Larcher ?
You need to give me something.
I've got diarrhea.
Go to the nursing station.
They'll give you a number.
A number ?   Shit !
I'm Michel Bellini, son of Roger Bellini,
President of the Chamber of Commerce.
Son of Bellini or not, go to the nursing station
and take a number. Wait your turn.
Excuse me, I represent the Mayor, it's very important.
I've had no news of my family for a week.
Get in the queue please.
There's an incredible queue... I already
tried yesterday but it was impossible.
I've got lots of things.
That's good.
You should take them to the nursing station.
Marie, we must talk.
But think, Monsieur Schwartz !
I hope Lorrain will return soon.
For sure he'll return.
So we have no future.
I can't lie to my husband, and see you in secret.
I never asked you that.
For now Lorrain isn't here.
He'll come back, but he's not here yet.
I feel the more we see each other
the harder it will be to stop.
Be near the bridge on the hill above the road.
It's not right Monsieur Schwartz.
Just to say goodbye.
A real goodbye.
I don't know.
Good day. Do I take a number here ?
Yes.
I'm Michel Bellini.
The doctor said I have priority.
Good. If he said so then go in.
Good day Mademoiselle.
That's... that was Madame Berthier.
She had a son in my class.
Thank you.
What's your name again ?
Michel Bellini.
There's another one.
Put her there.
I think she's the last.
Well I hope so.
What is wrong with you ?
I'm OK.
I can wait.
Te Quiero, doesn't that mean "I love you" ?
It's sad to end up dying of the runs.
Yes... I'm still here.
Daniel !
He's eaten, but he's ill. He's got diarrhea.
He needs a transfusion quickly.
How are you going to find
a vein in his arm at his age ?
I'll inject him in the fontanel.
Bring me the saline from over there please.
Where were you ?
A nun wanted to take him from me,
to send him to the orphanage.
Daniel, save him I beg you.
Hold his head steady.
It mustn't move.
On a count of three I'll inject him.
One... two... three
He's not out of the woods yet.
We need sulfonamides.
Find him some diapers. He needs changing.
There you are.
Sleep very well my darling.
I'm going to change you.
You know darling.. I don't want you
to deceive yourself...
You're imagining a future.
We can't keep him indefinitely.
I know.
Micheline !
The guy down there with the armband...
It's the guy from the other day...
...the one next to the Shepherd.
He's from Intelligence. It's him
that's tracking the cell.
He's young for a guy from Intelligence.
What's he doing here ?
Papa !
Is the doctor here ?
Is my brother here ?
I need to give you a number.
A number ?... Daniel !
He's not here, he's...
Daniel !
She had an attack, as you said.
Here, Micheline.
As I told you, she has to get out of here.
Docteur Moret said...
...at least I understood... that if she
took sulfonamides she'd be better.
He didn't. You misunderstood.
Anyway I don't have any.
I think there are two left Docteur.
Believe me Marcel, a sulfonamide is pointless.
Take her out of this fetid air and get her rested.
She said there are still tablets.
There are some, but for
patients who have a real need.
So, if your wife's health matters
more than pestering me ...
... take her hand and get her out of here.
Couldn't you close it ?
You really have a knack for messing things up.
Docteur. I can't.. I can't continue your....
Please. You have to sign
the death certificate for this woman.
No, It's me...
Docteur ?
Docteur, can you give me something for my diarrhea ?
Not now.
Hortense.
What is it ?
Te Quiero's mother is just outside.
She's dead.
Docteur.
Excuse me. I got hold of the guy at the Préfecture.
He can't do anything. The Germans control everything.
... but he told me that
a medical truck was in the ditch...
...near the hamlet of La Vierge.
It happened an hour ago.
Finally some good news if it's true.
Shall I go ?
No. It needs someone who knows medicines.
Darling. I've got to stay here.
Will you go and find some sulfonamides ?
Yes.
Go on then ! The baby's life depends on it.
Is Inspecteur Marchetti still out there ?
Yes, he's busy with victims.
Ask him to accompany you. I'll make a list.
Give him to me.
I've got him.
Your husband is doing well.
He impresses me.
He's a marvellous man.
Very devoted to others.
He has really been the chance of my life.
You've recovered very well from giving birth.
Giving birth ?
Well, the baby just now. It's not yours ?
No.
No, no, it's not mine.
You seem to love it anyway.
Yes.
Hold on. Over there !
Wait !
Wait, don't move.
How are you ?
You're injured.
I'm OK !
Not bad work for a minder, eh ?
I didn't see him coming.....the bastard !
Are you alright ?
Yes
A second tube of 30 tablets.
It feels like Christmas.
With that the baby will live, and I can curb the epidemic.
Madame Larcher ?
Can you tell us what became of that child you brought us ?
Te Quiero.
Bloody diarrhea. My wife brought him to me...
We only just saved him.
Can I take him ?
No, not now.
Not before evening.
Or tomorrow, he's still very weak.
You saw what happened to the other baby ?
Monsieur Larcher, excuse me speaking frankly
but the baby has parents somewhere.
In fact they're both dead Sister.
Yes but he has a family... grandparents,
uncles, aunts... who knows ?
Listen, once he's stable I'll bring him to you myself.
I'll depend on you Monsieur Larcher.
You can.
You're going to give him up ?
The Sister's right. He has a family somewhere.
Yes, where ? In Spain, in a grave.
Daniel, Daniel. I know you agree with me.
I saw it just now in your eyes.
Hortense.
I promised to take him back.
They're going give him to the State.
One orphan amongst hundreds. Daniel !
He's so small, so ill.
We'll give him back later.
Attention !
And now Larcher, what are you doing ?
We've retrieved the weapons and
are in process of stopping an epidemic.
What is that ?
They're official armbands. I'm having
them worn by everyone in charge here.
I demand that you remove them immediately, Docteur.
Why ? You're joking.
The Tricolour flag is now strictly forbidden.
Its presence will be considered
hostile to the German Army.
Can't you do anything for this smell Docteur ?
It's terrible.
We need to evacuate some of the people.
But we haven't the means to make them leave.
Now I begin to understand why you've lost this war.
Here are the directives of the German
Military Government in France.
You must have them respected...
...scrupulously by the population.
The penalties for failure are very severe.
Moreover, according to our information...
It's in German !
Communist émigrés from the Reich...
Austrians sought by our Police...
...have taken refuge here.
One of them is a great enemy of the German people.
If he's an Austrian, how is he our concern ?
He's one of the persons that your government,
in the Armistice Convention...
... has promised to deliver to Germany.
But the Armistice doesn't take effect until tomorrow.
Should I close the doors of the church
with you all inside, and not return until tomorrow ?
It's up to you.
Any help given to this criminal
will be severely punished.
He said to ransack the church.
If the guy flees they'll fire in the air once and then....
And then we'll see. I think...
From sunset until...
No reason to support this guy.
He's a Communist and shit stirrer !
That's got nothing to do with it.
I shook hands and made a deal...
I'll not lift a finger, however !
You're going to give him his morphine ?
Unbeknown to the Germans ?
Where has he gone ?
Docteur. I'm tired. I have to go back.
I'll return tomorrow, but I don't know when.
I've the animals to care for.
Thank you.
If they know that we're protecting him
we'll be in big, big trouble.
How will we explain that we didn't speak up earlier.
When they find them, we'll have troubles.
Would you tell them "He's the guy" ?
Yes. Whatever you wish.
But I'll respect your decision.
Any civilian who in any way participates in combat...
... or lends aid to the enemy will be treated...
We say nothing to the Germans,
we give nothing to the Spaniards.
Halt !
Hortense !
Daniel !
It's over.
Go home now.
And take the baby.
At least we've avoided panic.
Yes.
It's all thanks to you.
I think you're going to have to
assume the functions of Mayor, Docteur.
Temporarily.
You're joking ?
The Mayor will soon return.
We don't know that.
From tomorrow we'll have to
face up to a multitude of problems.
Rehousing... provisioning...
... various acquisitions.
Its going to need someone to take decisions.
Today you've shown that you're the man of the hour.
You're sure that it's legal ?
It's a case of force majeure.
I'll have to think about it.
I was frightened that you wouldn't come.
I'll never let anything separate us. Never.
Subtitles by R Clarke.
Whitby, Ont. Jan 2014